Another signal.
The source of the signal must be close.
I have to climb up to the Tallneck's head.
The killers.
What are they doing here?
[Eclipse thug]
What use is a Tallneck? They don't even fight.
That nearly skewered me!
[Eclipse thug]
To arms!
It looks like they're trying to capture the Tallneck.
[Eclipse thug]
Whose body is this?
This one's dead!
So they woke up.
[Eclipse priest]
Who's shooting?
Move along now.
They're giving up.
Rost always said "patience".
Okay, I need to get up to the Tallneck's head.
I should be able to jump onto the Tallneck from here.
Okay, time to climb up to its head.
I'll find a use for you.
These are helpful.
Bitter, though.
Calm, calm.
Abandoned.
A lot of dead machines.
Are those tooth marks on that machine?
Who is that?
Tribal girl.
You're a hunter, machine hunter.
I can smell it on you.
Their oils and fluids.
Oh, your hands are stained.
Can I just scent your fingers?
Uhhh, no.
No, no, no, no, of course not, no.
Forgive me, my head, it's … it's addled.
Heavy with the taste of metal and lightning and prophecy.
Do you dream of the Metal World huntress?
That's what you Nora call it.
The ancient world?
Yes. Yes!
You've almost touched it.
You hunt the machine, strip the parts, reach into their guts.
Let the sacred fluids run out.
Spilling away into the earth, wasted.
Open your mouth to insight.
Drink up, that's what I did.
I'm Brin.
Uh, you're Banuk. Is this normal for your tribe?
My tribe? My tribe? My tribe?
No tribe!
The other Shaman said, "You've drunk in the machine spirit's madness."
They said, "This is not the way of things!"
Stripped me out on the ice, left me to die.
Said, "That's the way of things."
Cold unending.
They cast you out.
But you survived.
Perhaps.
I remember the chill, pressed in slow, spear-tipped.
Tallnecks gathering their great dark heads over me like a garland.
Then I was walking again.
Walking back to my once-tribe.
To return is to be forgiven, but I kept walking.
No-one stopped me.
Those wounds.
A Sawtooth gave them to you on the hunt didn't it?
Oh, not just any Sawtooth, not just a hunt.
I was low, quiet in the long grass, spear at the ready to bring it down.
Then the scent, the taste of its blood overcame me.
I pounced, wrestled it down, bit into it.
So close! A shiver through my teeth as they ground along the wires.
But its teeth won out.
You're lucky to be alive, I think.
Until the wounds mend, flower into scars, only my mind can wander.
But why not trade, huntress?
You bring me the blood.
I tell you what it reveals.
You really drink the blood of machines?
I heard tales of a tribe from the land where the sun goes at night.
They were suckled from the machines.
No, no, no, it's true.
Took wisdom and strength from it, drew closer to them.
Then the tales go dark.
A whole tribe disappeared.
Maybe because they all died?
Drinking machine blood can't be good for you.
Uh, first it made me sick.
Then came the visions, for days and nights.
Machine dreams, huntress.
These dreams you have…?
Oh, you're curious. Good!
It'll give you a long life.
I wish that for you. That's my blessing.
Now we're sworn, I'll tell you how the visions began.
All is silence. The sky is dark.
I gather up the world and peel it back.
Expose the ancient metal beneath, like skinning a rabbit.
It's warm to the touch, warm as the sun pressed against it.
I feel sound.
My heartbeat is the thunder of titans rising!
Machines bigger than mountains, stronger too!
The Metal World carried on their shoulders.
I'm not sure I like these visions of yours.
Th-th-th-they're an answer!
But to what questions?
I must know.
I'll share?
It's been interesting, but I should be on my way.
Roam far, huntress.
And remember, the blood is precious to me, yes.
Good hunting at the Ridge of Veils.
If you fell a Sawtooth bring me what spills, won't you?
Not enough metal in the rain water.
Not for my taste.
Or maybe too much.
Dust feels like it's under my skin.
Need to keep the upper hand.
The wire isn't long enough.
Now they're hunting me.
Brin says the blood is precious.
Okay.
Ah, huntress!
You've brought me the blood of the Sawtooth.
Yes, I smelled it a hill away.
Don't make me regret it.
No matter what you hear, what screams, keep your distance.
Starting to regret it.
Before the time of the Sawtooth, the machines ran as one pack.
Metal drumming on metal, keeping pace out to the lightning's edge.
The rumble of low storms, that's them in motion.
And then a confusion.
Something has changed.
The great direction breaks, splits off like a dead branch.
They're tumbling now. When they recover, violence is what they know.
Now metal screeches on metal.
A death dance.
Learned from wars before our eyes had learned to see.
The Sawtooth, the Ravager, they hunt in the long shadows of others.
Jagged shapes, old shapes, with bloody eyes.
And the machines no longer rise and swell as one thing, an all-thing.
You're quite the storyteller.
But what's it mean?
Oh, meaning is not for me to say. Only what I saw.
And you saw all that?
Yes!
Doesn't it make you wonder?
The machines that drive other machines mad.
Corruptors! It's their venom I must taste next.
Do you have any idea what that could do to you?
You've drunk it before, of course you have.
I found fallen ones on Coiled Canyon's cliffs.
Under the sun, it boiled inside them.
The vapour, intoxicating!
Save these for the trail.
Uh-oh, spotted!
Now they're hunting me.
Ha ha!
Ugh, the stink!
Stocking up.
Sunset, maybe a chance to rest.
They're scanning for me.
Can stop tensing up.
Just stay out of their way for now.
So did you smell this blood coming? It stinks.
The richest is not always the sweetest, huntress.
In the jungles of the Jewel a fruit grows but reeks of spoiled meat.
Taste it though, honey to the tongue!
No.
This is disgusting.
These Corruptors never belonged to the herds.
They crawl from beneath desert or rust, from the bones of old machines.
Sickness to spread.
That's how they came.
Cold metal runs hot, buckles with thorn cuts and tail stings.
A fever of obedience.
My ears are ringing!
I grasp at my tongue, an ingot falls out, stamped with circles and lines.
Directions, instructions, to break a machine's will.
I heard the metal screaming, huntress.
I leave the ingot where it falls.
This isn't for us to know.
Corruptor after Corruptor tramples it in their greedy tread.
That is how they work.
Kind of.
How do you know these things?
It's not what I know, huntress.
It's what the blood knows.
Am I the singer or the song?
I don't know what you are.
Maybe get some rest.
No rest when there's unknown journeys to prepare for.
Do you know of the hidden machines that hunt men deep in the Jewel?
Stalkers? Yes, I know of them.
Oh, Stalker blood next?
Sure, why not.
Change comes in rushes, huntress, like time around an arrow.